Kevin L. Miller, Ph.D.

Los Angeles, CA 90230

LinkedIn: https://linkedin.com/in/kevin-miller-1b197986/ | GitHub: https://github.com/Koldenblue

Portfolio: https://koldenblue.github.io/kevin-miller-portfolio/

klmille@gmail.com | (310) 562-4572

SUMMARY

Full-Stack Web Developer with a Ph.D. in chemistry from the University of California, Los Angeles (UCLA). Experienced problem-solver and scientific researcher with major publications. Values ethics, integrity, and good business sense, having spent years as a business manager and scientist. Extensive teaching experience stems from being both a classroom teacher and a group fitness leader, which lend themselves to public speaking and teamwork skills. Top aim is to contribute to a team while continuously improving coding skills. Seeks to improve the lives of both teammates and clients, whether that be in the real world or the digital world.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Main coding written in JavaScript/HTML/CSS for web applications
- Coding techniques include object-oriented programming, asynchronous function handling, Application Programming Interface (API) integration with apps, responsive web design, client-server communication, interface design, and code testing
- Python and C/C++ programming accomplished through self-study and professional certification
- JavaScript libraries include Node.js, jQuery, Express, Bootstrap, and Handlebars
- Database work done with Structured Query Language (SQL) through MySQL

PROJECTS

Trek App | https://github.com/rbraun04/Trek | https://rbraun04.github.io/Trek/

- An app that maps out a day's journey to the great outdoors hiking, eating, directions, and weather. A collaborative project.
- Performed lead scripting, as well as scripting for all Google Maps API calls. Written in JavaScript/HTML/CSS.

Readme Generator | https://github.com/Koldenblue/readme-generator

- Quickly generates readmes in markdown format. Promotes good documentation and licensing practices. Practical program with planned updates.
- Mainly utilizes promise-based programming. Written in JavaScript and runs in Node.js.

Chess | https://github.com/Koldenblue/python-chess-game

- Written using two different methods, alternatively utilizing sequential programming and objectoriented principles. Excellently demonstrates of the strengths of object-oriented programming.
- Written in Python for use in a terminal.

EMPLOYMENT

Twinwood, Inc.:

Property Manager and Accountant

October 2013 - Present

- Rigorous documentation and coordination of large construction projects, with spending ranges in the hundreds of thousands of dollars, directly benefited both tenants and the company
- Meticulous business analytics helped achieve a yearly company growth rate of 3.6% of net worth

Praxair:

• Carefully managed lab testing allowed for a fast throughput of dozens of highly pure gasses daily

University of California, Los Angeles:

Researcher / Teaching Assistant

Sept. 2007 - July 2013

- Intense scientific research led to seven published research papers
- Personal mentoring of two undergraduates helped them publish their own scientific papers
- Chemistry research was awarded Ralph and Charlene Bauer Award, and led to two separate fellowship awards
- Close supervision was performed for hundreds of undergraduate students in both labs and discussion sections, during teaching of over a dozen college-level chemistry discussion courses

EDUCATION

Coding Bootcamp - UCLA Extension CS50 Professional Certificate - HarvardX Online Ph.D., Chemistry - University of California, Los Angeles B.S., Chemistry - University of California, Irvine To be completed, October 2020 To be completed, October 2020

> Dec. 2014 June 2007

LEADERSHIP, COMMUNITY, AND ADDITIONAL SKILLS

Fitness Instructor at Santa Monica Family YMCA

Oct. 2017 - Present

- Consistent teaching of public-facing kickboxing and choreographed dance requires an ingrained positive team mentality
- Enthusiasm for teaching led to a fellowship award for dance
- Certified in CPR / AED, Pediatric CPR, and First Aid by the American Red Cross

Music

• Self-taught bass and guitar skills, a background in music theory, and experience with classical trombone have led to collaborations on a published album and various public shows